Aaron Walker

hello.vcra.io | github.com/vcra | linkedin.com/in/awalker-vcra | aaron@vcra.io

PROFILE

SRE and DevOps Engineer. Experience with Python, Kubernetes, Django, CI/CD, IaC and Automation

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Python 3, Java, Kotlin, Arduino C, golang, Android

Observability and Monitoring

Prometheus, Grafana, FluentBit, FluentD, Elastic Stack, Loki

Databases

Relational: PostgreSQL, MySQL/MariaDB, NoSQL: Redis, ElasticSearch

Cloud Technologies

Kubernetes,
AWS, GCP, Azure, Openstack, vRA
Heroku, CloudFoundry

Version Control

Git & SVN GitHub, GitLab, Bitbucket

Testing and Documentation

PyTest, Junit, Espresso and Selenium Sphinx, Swagger

CI/CD & Automation

CI/CD: GitLab CI/CD, Argo CD, Travis, Jenkins, Concourse Automation: Ansible, Terraform

Web Technologies

Backend: Django, Flask **Frontend**: SASS, JQuery

Other

K8s Operator framework, Hashicorp Vault, JIRA, Confluence, MQTT, Istio, Ngnix

EXPERIENCE

Associate SRE Engineer at Sky UK

September 2019 – Current

Designed and deployed Source-to-Image (S2I) Kubernetes cluster using CloudFoundry, RKE and OpenStack. Developed and operated Service Broker to allow for DBaaS deployments atop K8s. Managed monitoring & logging stacks using Prometheus, Loki & Grafana.

Initiated project to overhaul neglected internal services, improving security, regaining observability and increasing reliability.

President at AberCompSoc, Aberystwyth University

August 2018 – June 2019

Organising the student-run Computer Science Society at Aberystwyth University. Included organising trips, such as FOSDEM 2019, holding meetings, allocating budget, working with external organisations such as the BCS and the University, and networking with students.

Software Development Trainee (Python/DevOps) at Amadeus Germany

July 2017 - September 2018

Developing full-stack Web-Applications using Django. Writing Unit and UI tests with Python and Selenium. Documentation using Sphinx. Developed an IoT Robotics Management Framework with microservices, using MQTT and ELK stack, and hosted on AWS. Creating and managing dashboards using Grafana.

Student Subject Ambassador & Demonstrator at Aberystwyth University

February 2016 - Current

Advertising the University to prospective applicants. Helping current students with tasks for workshops and practicals.

Network Support Placement at Stonyhurst College

July 2015 - August 2015

Disk image creation and deployment, cable management, chromebook deployments, Active Directory Configuration, VDI Deployment, IP Phones, Printers, switch configuration, Server rack mounting, Windows Server installation. Technologies included MS Hyper-V, Dell KACE, Dell WYSE, Dell Powerconnect.

PROJECTS

AberCompSoc Website

A website for AberCompSoc

Source: https://github.com/abercompsoc/website
Demo: http://abercs.herokuapp.com/

Bucaneer

A Simple pirate board game, made with Java Source: https://github.com/vCra/Buccaneer

LanguageFlip

An Android App to help you learn a language, made in Kotlin Source: https://github.com/vCra/LanguageFlip

Judge0api

A python client Library for judge0 – an online Judge system Source: https://github.com/vCra/judge0api

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Software Engineering (with integrated placement year) [2015-2019]
 2:1 - Computer Science (BEng) at Aberystwyth University

A-Level [2013-2015]

A-levels in Computing and Media Studies at Burnley College

• GCSE [2011-2013]

10 GCSE's, including an A* in English and an A in Mathematics.

Volunteering

FOSDEM Volunteer (2018, 2019, 2020)

Academic Representative – Computer Science

Aberystwyth Students Union A-Team

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATES

Stonyhurst College NCO Cadre Certificate 2013

RoboCup UK 2014 Junior Soccer National Finalist

Duke of Edinburgh Bronze Award

National Citizen Service Award 2013

REFERENCES

Mr. Kristian Schuhmacher, Senior Innovation Engineer Dr. Antonio Anjos, Lecturer in Computer Science

Amadeus Germany GmbH Aberystwyth University Email: kristian.schuhmacher@de.amadeus.com Email: ara11@aber.ac.uk

Phone: +49 6172 91-2882 Phone: +44 (0) 1970 622950